All right. that's the last servo.
C'était le dernier servomoteur.
Behold the Mobile Omnidirectional Neutralization and Termination Eradicator.
Voici la Machine Omnidirectionnelle de Neutralisation Terminale et d'Eradication.
Or--
- Alias... - Monte.
Featuring one articulated razor-sharp killing saw...
Avec sa scie tueuse articulée affûtée,
...one polycarbonate grinding wheel...
sa meule en polycarbonate,
...steel-armor plate exoskeleton top and bottom.
et son excsquelette en acier—blindé.
Enough horsepower to drive 110 pounds of mechanized death...
Sa puissance permet a cette machine tueuse de 50 kg
...from zero to holy crap in 4.8 seconds.
de passer de zéro à putain de merde en 4,8 secondes.
Is it wrong to say I love our killer robot?
C‘est mal de dire que j'aime notre robot-tueur ?
As with my father. I both love and fear it.
Comme pour mon père, je l'aime et je le crains.
All right. enough chitchat. Let's destroy something.
Assez de bavardage. Détruiscns quelque chose.
ALL: One. two. three. Unh.
- Un, deux, trois.
RAJESH: Okay. what shall be first to taste the wrath of Monte?
Avec quoi teste-t-on les foudres de Monte ?
Maybe we should start small.
On devrait commencer petit.
RAJESH: Okay. Oh. perhaps today is the day we finally find out...
Peut-être qu‘on va enfin découvrir
...what's inside the Magic 8 Ball.
ce qui se cache dans la boule magique 8.
Did it when l was 4.
Je l'ai fait a 4 ans.
It's an icosahedral die floating in tinted blue water.
C‘est un dé icosaèdre flottant dans un liquide bleu.
Man. call spoiler alert before you say things like that.
Préviens avant de dire ce genre de chose.
How about the toaster oven?
Pourquoi pas le petit four ?
What did the toaster oven ever do to you?
Qu‘est—ce qu'il t‘a fait ?
What did I do to Jimmy Mullins in the third grade?
Qu‘est—ce que j'ai fait a Jimmy Mullins a l‘école ?
He still punched me in the face with my own fists.
Il m‘a pourtant frappé au visage avec mon propre poing.
Sorry. you little nerd. You were just in the wrong boys' room at the wrong time.
Désolé bizut, tu étais au mauvais endroit au mauvais moment.
Gentlemen. goggles.
Messieurs, lunettes.
Yeah. this is an auspicious moment.
C‘est un grand moment.
Like Robert Oppenheimer or Neil Armstrong...
Tout comme Robert Oppenheimer ou Neil Armstrong,
...we need the appropriate words to mark this historic scientific event.
il nous faut trouver les mots pour marquer cet évènement scientifique historique.
How about. "Die. toaster. die“?
Pourquoi pas, "Grève, four, crève ?“
That'll do it.
Ça le fait.
All right. what's next?
Au suivant.
No. I think I'm just gonna stay in tonight and do laundry.
Non, je vais juste rester a la maison et faire ma lessive.
Oh. yeah. This door got the full monty.
Cette porte s‘est faite démontée.
PENNY: Leonard? -Uh-huh?
Léonard ?
What the hell?
C‘est quoi ce cirque ?
-A killer robot. We built it. -Yeah. well. it almost killed me.
- C‘est le robot—tueur qu'on a construit. - Ça a failli me tuer.
If it wanted to kill you. you'd be dead.
S'il l‘avait voulu, tu serais morte.
So who exactly does it wanna kill?
Et ca veut tuer qui exactement ?
I'm sorry. are you unaware of the upcoming...
Pardon, mais tu ignorés que va débuter prochainement
...Southern California Robot Fighting League Round Robin Invitational?
la Compétition dela Ligue de Combat de Robots de Californie du Sud ?
You know. since I moved last year. not all my mail has been forwarded.
Tu sais, depuis mon déménagement, tout mon courrier n‘a pas suivi.
It's a big deal. heh.
C‘est un événement majeur.
There's an awards banquet and a dance afterward.
Il y a un banquet de remise des prix et un bal.
Perhaps you'd like to come with me.
Peut-être voudrais-tu m'y accompagner.
I know the other fellas would be really excited to see a girl there.
Les autres seraient tout excités d'y voir une fille.
How is it supposed to be a dance if I'm the only girl?
Un bal sans fille ?
Well. that may be a slight exaggeration.
Bon, c‘est un peu exagéré.
You'd be the only doable girl.
Tu serais la seule fille mettable.
You're a pig. Howard.
Tu es un porc, Howard.
How is doable anything but a compliment?
“Mettable", mais c‘est un compliment ?
-Why don't we work on the robot? -Please. Leonard. not now.
- Et si on bossait sur le robot ? - Pas maintenant, Leonard.
Once again. Penny and l have begun our little tango.
Une fois encore, Penny et moi avons commencé notre petit tango.
Our-- Our tango?
Notre tango ?
The carnal repartee. the erotic to and fro.
L‘échange charnel, Ie va-et-vient érotique.
But as delicious as the appetizer might be...
Mais aussi délicieux les amuse—gueules soient-ils,
...at some point we will have to succumb and eat the entrée while it's still...
il nous faudra succomber à l'entrée tant qu'elle est encore
...hot.
chaude.
I'm begging you. stop talking.
Je t'en prie, tais—toi
Look. normally. I can just ignore you.
D‘habitude, j‘arrive a t'ignorer.
I mean. I get it. You're a little peculiar. Like Sheldon.
Je comprends. Tu es étrange. Gomme Sheldon.
Yeah. excuse me. Penny. but in this room. you're the one who's peculiar.
Excuse—moi Penny, mais dans cette pièce, c‘est toi qui es étrange.
Yeah. you might be right.
Tu as probablement raison.
But back to you. You think you're some sort of smooth-talking ladies' man...
A toi. Tu crois que tu charmes les femmes avec ton bagou
...but the truth is you are just pathetic and creepy.
mais en Vérité, tu es juste pathétique et affreux.
So. what are you saying?
Où veux-tu en venir ?
I am saying it is not a compliment to call me doable.
C‘est pas un compliment de me dire que je suis mettable.
It is not sexy to stare at my ass and say:
Fixer mes fesses n‘est pas sexy
[AS HOWARD] “Ooh, it must be jelly, because jam don't shake like that.“
ni dire, “Ce doit être dela gelée, la confiture bouge pas comme ca.“
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Most important. we are not dancing a tango.
Et par-dessus tout, on ne danse pas le tango.
We're not to-ing and fro-ing.
Ni ne faisons de va-et-vient.
Nothing is ever gonna happen between us. Ever.
Il ne se passera jamais rien entre nous.
Wait a minute. This isn't flirting. You're serious.
Une minute. On n‘est pas en train de flirter. T'es sérieuse.
Flirting? You think I'm flirting with you? I am not flirting with you.
Tu crois que je flirte avec toi ? Je ne flirte pas avec toi.
No woman is ever gonna flirt with you. You're just gonna grow old and die alone.
Aucune femme ne flirtera avec toi. Tu vas vieillir et mourir seul.
Thanks for the heads up.
Merci du renseignement.
-Howard. where are you going? -|'m going home...
- Howard, où tu vas ? - Chez moi
...to live my creepy. pathetic life.
Vivre mon affreuse et pathétique vie.
Well. y-- Someone had to say it.
Il fallait lui dire.
-What? -Uh. he said maybe we should enter you...
- Quoi ? - Il a dit qu'on devrait peut-ètre t'inscrire
...in the killer-robot competition.
a la compétition du robot-tueur.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard. the phone is ringing!
Howard, téléphoné.
Here's a crazy idea. Ma: answer it!
Voilà une suggestion dingue : réponds.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Hello?
Allô ?
All right. hold on.
Bien, un instant.
It's your friend. Leonard!
C‘est ton ami, Leonard.
He wants to know why you're not at school today.
Il veut savoir pourquoi t'es pas a l'école.
ldon't go to school. Ma.
Je vais pas a l'école, m'man.
| work at a university.
Je travaille dans une université.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: That's a school. Now pick up the phone.
C‘est une école. Décroche.
I don't wanna talk to anybody.
Je veux parler a personne.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Should I ask Leonard to bring over your homework?
Je demande a Léonard de te ramener tes devoirs ?
I don't have homework.
J'ai pas de devoirs.
I'm a grown man with a Master's degree in Engineering!
Je suis grand et j'ai un master en Ingénierie !
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Excuse me. Mr. Fancy-Pants.
Excusez-moi, M. Prétentieux.
Want me to get you a popsicle?
Tu veux une glace ?
Cherry. please.
Ala cerise, s'il te plaît.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: I ate the cherry. All that's left is green.
Je l'ai mangée. Il reste plus que du vert.
You make me wanna kill myself.
Tu me donnes envie de me suicider.
-What's going on? -I don't know.
- Alors ? - Je sais pas.
Now they're just yelling about popsicles.
Ils parlent de glaces en hurlant.
-Sounds like Penny really got to him. -|'m not surprised.
- Penny lui a fait du mal. - Je suis pas surpris.
Despite his hard and crusty shell. Howard is a very sensitive man.
Sous sa carapace, Howard est un homme très sensible.
Do you know he writes poetry?
Tu sais qu'il écrit dela poésie ?
Mostly about men from Nantucket and hermits named Dave...
Principalement sur des hommes de Nantucket et sur des ermites,
...but he does it with real sensitivity.
mais avec beaucoup de sensibilité.
[LISPING] Hey. Hofstadter.
Salut, Hofstadter.
Word around the plasma lab is you built a robot?
Il parait que tu as construit un robot ?
-Yes. we did. Kripke. -His name is Monte.
- En effet, Kripke. - Il s‘appelle Monté.
Well. if you have any delusions about entering him against the Kripke Crippler...
Si vous pensez qu'il peut battre mon robot, Ie Kripke Crippler
...in the Southern California Robot Fighting...
dans la Compétition dela Ligue de Combat de Robots de Californie du Sud
...AKA the SCRFLRRI...
ou la CLCWCS,
...his name is gonna be Scrap Metal.
on l‘appellera alors “Débris de Métal".
Come on. Is that really necessary?
Allez. On est obligé de faire ca ?
Leonard. I believe it is.
Leonard, oui il me semble.
This is trash talk.
Il nous fait affront.
Trash talk is a traditional component in all sporting events.
C‘est une caractéristique traditionnelle des événements sportifs.
Kripke...
Kripke.
...your robot is inferior and it will be defeated by ours...
ton robot est inférieur et sera vaincu par le nôtre,
...because ours exceeds yours in both design and execution.
car il surpasse le tien en conception et réalisation.
Also. I'm given to understand that your mother is overweight.
Et il me semble savoir que ta mère est en surpoids.
Oh. snap.
Dans les dents.
If that is a result of a glandular condition and not gluttony...
Si c‘est en raison d‘une maladie hormonale,
...I withdraw that comment.
je retire ce que j'ai dit.
What difference does it make? Fat is fat.
Il y a une différence ? Gros, c‘est gros.
There are boundaries.
Il y a des limités à tout.
Tell you what. forget the SCRFLRRI.
Vous savez quoi, oubliez Ia CLCWCS.
-Let's settle this roboto a roboto. -What do you mean?
- On va régler ça roboto a roboto. - Pardon ?
There's no guarantee we're gonna go against each other. so let's throw down.
On est pas sûr de s'affronter, donc il faut anticiper.
You know. unless you're afraid.
A moins que vous ayez peur.
We accept your challenge. Name a time and place.
On accepte de relever le défi. Donne ton heure et le lieu.
-Tomorrow. 3:00. the kinetics lab. -Make it so.
- Demain, 15 h, au labo cinétique. - Ainsi soit—il.
No. don't make it so.
Non, impossible.
Barry. we can't fight you tomorrow. Our engineer is incapacitated.
Barry, on ne peut pas se battre demain. Notre ingénieur est indisposé.
What's wrong with him?
Qu‘est—ce qu'il a ?
He's depressed because he's pathetic and creepy and can't get girls.
Il est déprimé parce qu'il est pathétique, affreux et indésirable.
We're all pathetic and creepy and can't get girls.
C‘est notre cas a tous.
That's why we fight robots.
C‘est pour ça qu'on se bat contre des robots.
If you're not there. you'll be exposed to ridicule.
Si vous ne vous montrez pas, vous risquez d‘étre ridicules.
I'm curious. what part of America is that accent from?
Je me demande, de quel coin des USA Vient son accent ?
-Hey. -Hey. you got a minute?
T'as une minute ?
Yeah. come on in. What's up?
Oui, entré. Qu‘est—ce qui se passe ?
-I need you to apologize to Howard-- -Get out.
- Tu dois faire tes excuses à Howard... - Sors.
Come on. Wolowitz won't come out of his house and we need him for a robot battle.
Allez. Wolowitz ne sort plus et on a besoin de lui pour notre duel de robots.
Then have the robot go and get him.
Demande au robot d‘aller le chercher.
-The robot didn't hurt his feelings. -His feelings needed to be hurt.
- C‘est pas le robot qui lui a fait du mal. - Il fallait lui faire du mal.
He's been in bed for two days.
Ca fait deux jours qu'il est au lit.
Yeah. probably with a blow-up doll.
Oui, sûrement avec une poupée gonflable.
He's not with a--
Il n‘est pas...
Does it really matter who or what he's with?
C‘est pas le problème.
The-- The guy is devastated.
Il est anéanti.
Oh. please. How could I possibly devastate Howard?
Oh, je t'en prie, comment j'aurais pu anéantir Howard ?
Okay. don't take this as a criticism...
Ne le prends pas mal,
...but you do kind of have that...
mais c‘est comme si tu étais exposée aux rayons gamma.
What does that mean?
Excuse—moi ?
You know. Like. most of the time. you're the easygoing Bruce Banner.
D'habitude tu es le gentil Bruce Banner.
But then when you get angry. you kind of turn into like. you know:
Mais quand tu te fâches, tu te transformés en, tu sais :
I turn into a bear?
En ours ?
Seriously? Gamma rays? Bruce Banner?
Rayons X ? Bruce Banner ?
You didn't get The Incredible Hulk from that?
T'as pas compris que je parlais de L 'Incmyable Hulk ?
Never mind. Just-- Please. just go talk to him.
Tant pis. Va lui parler, s'il te plaît.
Oh. and say what? That I didn't mean it? Because I meant it.
Et lui dire quoi ? Que je ne le pensais pas ? Je le pensais.
Well. maybe you can go at it from a different angle.
Tu peux voir les choses sous un autre angle.
Like. you see a glimmer of goodness in him...
Comme si tu avais vu une lueur de bonté en lui
...and you only said what you said because...
et que tu as dit ça parce que tu voulais qu'elle éclose et qu'elle brillé.
Okay. let's try it this way.
Envisageons les choses autrement.
Remember the day we first met...
A notre rencontre,
...and you asked me to go to your boyfriend's...
tu m'as demandé d‘aller chez ton copain récupérer ta télé.
And he was 9 feet tall and he took my pants off and you said--
Il faisait 2 m de haut, il a enlevé mon pantalon et tu as dit...
What was that? What did you s--?
Qu‘est—ce que c‘était déjà ?
Oh. yes. You said you owed me one.
Ah oui, tu as dit que tu me le revaudrais.
Okay. come on. that's not fair.
C‘est injuste.
I came home with no pants.
Je suis rentré en caleçon.
Fine. I'll go over there tomorrow.
D‘accord. J'irai demain.
Thank you.
Merci.
I should probably give you a heads up about his mother.
Je devrais te prévenir a propos de sa mère.
What about her?
Qu‘est—ce qu'elle a ?
She's a delightful woman. You'll love her.
C‘est une femme excise. Tu vas l‘adorer.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard. there's a blond girl. Patsy. here to see you.
Howard, il y a une blonde, Patsy, qui veut te voir.
Who?
- Oui ? - Maintenant, elle dit s‘appeler Penny.
I don't wanna talk to her.
Je veux pas lui parler.
-Hey. -Ma.
- Salut. - Maman.
MRS. WOLOWITZ: She ran past me.
Elle m‘a doublée.
Was I supposed to tackle her?
Je devais lui faire un croche-pied ?
So I just came by to see how you were doing.
Je suis passée voir comment tu allais.
I'm fine.
Je vais bien.
Good.
Super.
Your mom seems nice.
Ta mère a l‘air gentil.
People move away from her on the bus.
Les gens l‘évitent dans le bus.
What do you want?
Tu veux quoi ?
Okay. look. Howard...
Bon, écouté, Howard.
...I just want to apologize.
je voudrais te présenter mes excuses.
For some things that I have said.
Pour certaines des choses que j'ai dites.
About you.
Sur toi.
I've been informed that you have feelings...
On m‘a appris que tu avais des sentiments
...and apparently. I have hurt them.
et visiblement, je t'ai fait du mal.
So I'm sorry.
Je suis donc désolée.
Howard.
Howard.
Fine. You're sorry. Goodbye.
Super. Tu es désolée. Ciao.
So you're okay?
Ca va aller ?
Hey. I'm a big boy.
Je suis un grand garçon.
I'm not traumatized by some random comment from some random woman.
Je m'offusque pas des paroles quelconques d‘une fille quelconque.
I mean. get over yourself.
Remets-toi.
Okay. Well...
Bon, eh bien,
...bye.
au revoir.
So close.
Si prés du but.
Oh. my God. That's Kripke's robot?
Oh, mon Dieu. C‘est le robot de Kripke ?
KRIPKE [ON COMPUTER]: As you can see...
Comme vous le voyez, le Crippler réduit en miettes Ie Chevy Cavalier.
I can't watch anymore.
Je peux plus regarder.
-She|don. we have to call it off. -We don't have that option.
- Sheldon, il faut annuler. - Impossible.
We've accepted the challenge. We can't run away from a fight.
On a accepté le défi. On ne peut pas lui tourner le dos.
Oh. please. We've spent our whole lives running away from fights.
Je t'en prie. C‘est ce qu'on a fait toute notre vie.
Personally. I can squeeze through a hole in a fence half my size.
Perso, je peux me glisser dans un trou deux fois plus petit que moi.
Well, impressive as that may be. Monte is not us.
Aussi impressionnant soit—ii, Monte n‘est pas nous.
Monte has no fear.
Monte n‘a peur de rien.
Sheldon. did we all not just watch the same video?
Sheldon, on a tous vu la même chose, non ?
Kripke's robot just had angry sex with a mid-sized automobile.
Le robot de Kripke Vient de se taper une voiture.
You are overlooking the fact we know what we're up against.
Tu oubliés qu'on sait à quoi s‘attendre.
And we can modify Monte so that he's prepared.
On peut préparer Monté.
You wanna prepare him?
Le préparer ?
Install a bladder and a pair of shorts so he can wet himself.
Lui mettre une vessie et un short qu'il puisse se pisser dessus.
How are we gonna make any modifications without Wolowitz?
Comment le modifier sans Wolowitz ?
-Have you heard from Penny? -Not yet.
- Des nouvelles de Penny ? - Pas encore.
Have faith. gentlemen.
Gardez espoir, messieurs.
We don't need Wolowitz.
On n‘a pas besoin de lui.
Engineering is merely the slow younger brother of physics.
L'ingénierie n‘est que le petit frère attardé de la physique.
Watch and learn.
Regardez et apprenez.
Do either of you know how to open the toolbox?
Vous savez ouvrir la boite a outils ?
And then when I was 14...
Et a 14 ans,
...I met Marcy Grossman.
j'ai rencontré Marcy Grossman.
She was so beautiful.
Elle était belle.
She just got her braces off...
On lui avait retiré son appareil,
...but they left a little of the overbite.
mais ses dents étaient encore un peu en avant.
It was so hot.
Tellement sexy.
Like a sexy little chipmunk.
Comme un adorable petit écureuil.
I didn't have the courage to ask her out...
J'ai pas eu le courage de l‘inviter à sortir avec moi,
...but I dedicated a song to her at the ninth-grade talent show.
mais je lui ai dédié une chanson au radio crochet en 3e.
Aw. that sounds sweet.
C‘est gentil.
[SINGING TO THE TUNE OF “MY GIRL“! Marcy Gmssman is sunshine
Marcy Grossman est mon rayon de soleil a‘ moi
On a cloudy day
Quand le temps est mauvais
When it's cold outside
Lorsqu 'il fait froid
Marcy Grossman is the month of May
Marcy Grossman est mon mois de mai
Oh. it's cute.
Oh, c‘est mignon.
I guess you'd say
J‘imagine que vous comprenez
What can make me feel this way?
Ce qui me fait cet effet ?
Marcy Grossman, Marcy Grossman, Marcy Grossman
Marcy Grossman, Marcy Grossman, Marcy Grossman
Talkin ' 'hout Marcy
Je vous parle de Marcy
That's great.
C‘est génial.
Grossman
Grossman
Ha. it's fun.
C‘est marrant.
And then she came up with that sexy little chipmunk mouth...
Et puis elle est venue me voir avec sa bouche sexy d'écureuil
...and spit in my hair.
et m‘a craché dans les cheveux.
Which brings us to 10th grade.
Ce qui nous amène en seconde.
Howard. do you think maybe sometimes...
Howard, tu crois pas que parfois
...you try too hard?
tu en fais un peu trop ?
Look at me.
Regarde-moi.
What chance do I have if I don't try too hard?
Quelles chances j'ai si j'en fais pas trop ?
Well. you have a terrific chance.
Tu as toutes tes chances.
You're smart. you're funny. you have a cool job.
Tu es intelligent, drôle. tu as un boulot cool.
You build stuff that goes into outer space.
Tu fabriqués des trucs qui vont dans l‘espace.
- I guess. - No. look...
On peut dire ca.
...I've known you for a year and a half...
Ca fait 1 an et demi que je te connais
...and this is the first time I feel like I'm talking to a real person.
et c‘est la première fois que j'ai l'impression
And you know what? I like him.
Et j'aime bien cette personne.
He's a nice guy.
Tu es un garcon gentil.
You really think so?
Tu le penses vraiment ?
Yes.
Oui.
I don't know.
Je sais pas.
No. I do.
Si je t‘assure.
Nice little bot you've got here.
Joli robot.
I'm aware.
Je sais.
What's this do. spin?
Ca fait quoi, ca tourne ?
Yep. At 3400 rpm.
Oui, 3 400 rotations a la minute.
It can cut through steel like it was rubber.
Ca rendre dans le métal comme dans du beurre.
Neat.
Cool.
Good work.
Bon travail.
Sheldon. we've gotta call this off.
Sheldon, il faut qu'on annulé.
No. Leonard.
Non, Leonard.
For years. merciless thugs like Kripke have made my life a series of painful noogies...
Pendant des années, des malfrats sans pitié
...and humiliating wedgies and the insensitively named Indian burns.
ont tiré sur mes slips ou m‘ont fait des brûlures indiennes.
-Well. that stops now. -She|don. we don't have a chance.
- La boucle est bouclée. - On a aucune chance.
The only improvement you were able to make...
La seule amélioration
...was to put fresh batteries in the remote.
a été de changer les piles dela télécommande.
What you fail to realize is Kripke suffers from a fatal flaw:
Vous oubliez que Kripke souffre d'un handicap fatal :
Overconfidence from his robot's massive size and its overwhelming power.
Il est trop confiant quant a la taille de son robot et son forcé.
That's not overconfidence. That's observation.
C‘est pas de la confiance. C‘est de l'observation.
Trust me. Kripke will fall easy prey to my psychological warfare. Observe.
Faites—moi confiance, Kripke va s'allonger face a ma guerre psychologique. Observez.
Kripke.
Kripke.
I would ask if your robot is prepared to meet its maker...
Ton robot est-il près à retrouver son créateur ?
...but as you are its maker. clearly the two of you have met.
Comme tu es son créateur, vous êtes déja ensemble.
What is his problem?
C‘est quoi son problème ?
Way to bust out the Jedi mind tricks. dude.
T'as massacré les techniques Jedi.
I wanna make sure that we're all clear.
Qu'on soit bien d‘accord.
Standard Robotic Fighting League rules apply.
On applique les régles dela Ligue.
Are you crazy?
T'es taré ?
This is a street fight.
C‘est un combat de rue.
The street has no rules.
Il n‘y a aucune règle.
He's right. Leonard. The paradigm is to the death.
Il a raison, Leonard. C‘est une lutte à mort.
I will. however. give you the opportunity to concede my superiority now...
Je vais vous donner l‘opportunité d'admettre maintenant ma supériorité
...and offer me your robot as the spoils of war.
et de m'offrir votre robot comme butin de guerre.
Never. I'd rather see Monte dead than in your hands.
Je préfère voir Monte mort plutôt qu‘entre tes mains.
That could be easily arranged.
Ca peut s‘arranger.
Ready. set. go?
Prêt, feu, partez ?
-Do it. -All right. then.
- Vas-y. - Trés bien.
Ready. set. go.
Prêt, feu, partez.
-Come on. Sheldon. you got this. -|ndeed.
- Vas-v, Sheldon, tu vas l'avoir. - En effet.
We are prepared for anything he can throw at us.
On est préparés à tout encaisser.
That's new.
Ca, c‘est nouveau.
Run. Monte. run.
Sauve-toi, Monté, sauve-toi.
RAJESH: Run. Monte. LEONARD: Go. Go. Monte. go.
- Sauve-toi, Monté. - Foncé, Monté, foncé.
-Run. Monte. -Go. go. go.
- Fuis, Monté. - Allez, allez.
Don't hurt us. don't hurt us. don't hurt us.
Ne nous fais pas de mal, ne nous fais pas de mai.
Well. so much for making up for the emotional wounds of childhood.
On n'aura pas réussi à compenser les blessures de l'enfance.
I did this.
C‘est ma faute.
Monte was killed by my hubris and my pride.
Monte a été tué par ma prétention et ma fierté.
No matter what anybody says. this is my fault.
Quoi qu'on en dise, c‘est ma faute.
No one's arguing with you. dude.
On va pas te contredire, mon pote.
I got your text. How bad is--? Oi.
J'ai eu votre message. Alors ?
Forget the robot. What happened to you?
Oublie le robot. Il t‘est arrivé quoi ?
-He slipped and fell. -Yes.
- Il est tombé. - Oui.
I slipped and fell.
J'ai glissé et je suis tombé.
In the bathroom.
Dans la salle de bain.
Bounced right off the tub.
De la baignoire.
Yes. Now he knows what bathtubs are capable of doing...
Il sait de quoi les baignoires sont capables
...when you don't treat them with respect.
quand on ne les traite pas avec respect.
Yeah.
Oui.
They sucker-punch you when your eyes are closed.
Elles te mettent une droite quand tu regardes pas.
So. what do you think. Howard?
Qu'en penses—tu, Howard ?
It-- It's not that bad. right?
C‘est grave ?
Yeah. no. A little electrical tape. some solder--
Non. De l‘adhésif électrique, des soudures...
Are you insane?
T'as pété une durite ?
I've seen space probes that crashed into...
J'ai vu des sondés spatiales s‘écraser alors qu‘elles étaient en meilleur état.
You're right.
Tu as raison.
Monte's gone.
Monte est mort.
We'll bury him in the morning. A simple ceremony. I'll speak.
On l‘enterrera au matin. Une cérémonie sobre. Je dirai un mot.
Leonard. you'll play your cello.
Leonard, tu joueras du violoncelle.
Sheldon. honey. aren't you getting a little carried away?
Sheldon, chéri, tu t'emballes ? C‘est qu'un robot.
Just a toy robot?
Qu'un robot ?
Penny.
Penny.
I know. I got it.
Je sais, j'y vais.
Sheldon? I'm sorry.
Sheldon ? Excuse-moi.
Well. don't get the wrong idea.
Ne vous méprenez pas.
The way I see it. I'm halfway to pity sex.
Je suis a deux doigts de l‘avoir par pitié.
[ENGLISH SDH]
[FRENCH]